# IRIS JIERONG ZHENG

1514 Hallgreen Dr, Walnut, CA 91789 jripzh@gmail.com • (626) 873-3497

linkedin.com/in/jierong-zheng-5374aa197/

#### SUMMARY:

5 years of experience in the Linux system and monitoring applications like Zabbix, Grafana at a global scale. Advanced knowledge of networking and open-source platforms. Monitoring over 1000 devices in global nodes across Dell, Juniper, Huawei and Cisco switch/routers and over 60 server systems.

### SKILLS:

# Systems|Technology

- Windows, Mac, Ubuntu, CentOS, Red Hat Linux, Amazon EC2
- Nginx, Apache, Haproxy, Tomcat, DNS, MySQL, Firewall, CDN
- Zabbix, Alerta, Grafana, Prometheus, Nagios, Cacti, Smokeping
- ELK, Splunk, Ansible, Docker, VMware, Python
- Confluence, Jira, Git
- OSPF, ACL, SNMP, SSH, TELNET, VLAN, Ethernet
- Customer Service, Troubleshooting

# Languages

- English, Mandarin Chinese

## **EXPERIENCE:**

Zenlayer Apr2017 - Jan2019

Senior Network Monitoring Engineer

- Shanghai, China - Architect monitoring platforms such as Zabbix, Alerta, Grafana, Smokeping.
- Monitor global network switch/router status, all nodes traffic, and network quality.
- Set threshold for traffic, device status, and network quality according to the current situation and notify the networking team to make adjustments.
- Troubleshoot, performance tuning and security hardening for monitoring platforms.
- Use Ansible to automate, configure, and upgrade over sixty server systems.
- Backup, optimize, upgrade database,
- Provide monthly traffic reports across global network footprint for further analysis and action.
- Track record of practical problem solving on Confluence.

Jinke Inc Apr2016 - Apr2017

Site Reliability Engineer

- Architect and maintain all websites of the company.
- Document processes for existing and scaling systems.
- Monitor and support production applications.
- Maintain and manage the company email system.
- Build, administer, and troubleshoot all mission critical environments.
- Maintain Git repositories for developers.

Zenlayer Jul2014 - Mar2016

Network Operations Center Engineer

- Acknowledge customer issues and resolve their problems quickly and efficiently.
- Troubleshoot/fix system/network issues.
- Plan and execute cutovers to optimize network environments.
- Assist teams to deliver solutions for customers.
- Install and configure Linux systems for customers.
- Maintain and update the Cacti and Nagios system.
- Virtualize physical servers and manage them via VMware tools.
- Working with enterprise hardware vendors to fix server, networking devices problems.
- Document customer tickets into a knowledge base for internal workflows.

# Got married and transitioned to the Status

Feb2019 - Current

Shanghai, China

Shanghai, China

### **EDUCATION:**

Huazhong University of Science and Technology; Computer Science, Jul2015

- CERTIFICATE:
  Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE), Jul2015
  Microsoft Certified Professional, Mar2014